PRATIBHA KAUR ARORA

Software Developer

Mob:-9990767635, 7906453553 Email:-pratibha.arora3593@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Software Developer with experience in Python Django framework MVC Model.

Enthusiastic about Research in Technology and want to contribute.

Experience with Google API's Integration and Automation on python framework – GTM, Google Adwords, Google Merchant Center and Google Analytics.

Strong interest in Algorithms and Data structures.

Worked on both Back-End and Front-End technologies on E-commerce Platform.

Built functionalities of CMS Architecture.

Believes in knowledge sharing platform and seeks to learn more technologies and Automation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Programming Languages</u>: Python, Javascript, Jquery, HTML, C & C++.

Database: Mysql, SQL, MongoDB.

Restful API: Django RestFramework

Framework: Django, Flask, AngularJs

<u>Version Controls</u>: GIT, Subversion.

Others: Celery - Asyn. Task Queue.

OS: Linux - Ubuntu Evironment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

	SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Ecom Express Pvt. Ltd. From 2017 to present. Developing and maintaining softwares for ecommerce modules like Tracking, Reporting, ERM, Billing, ERP etc. (https://ecomexpress.in/)
MODULE 1: Fleet Invoice Management	 The idea is to give transparency to manifestation from vendors. We made a system where system reads email via vendor, process them via cron and show reconciled data with our main server. There was a functionality to approve bill, reject invoices and accordingly it gives subtotal of a particular vendor manifest. I developed whole back-end for Email processing and API's with front-end server.
MODULE 2: Project: WarRoom Panel Authentication & Authorization	 Implemented Session Management on this project to handle user login and provided authorization for particular user to view data. Used django session and python tools to authenticate and authorize user on this panel. Also provided admin access to add user to role group to authorize particular template. Developed Front-end using AngularJs for pagination, search and other application features.
MODULE 3: Kateeye: Reporting Tool, Volume Tracker, Search Panel	 This module is their mainsite module for reporting as well as volume tracking. Developed with python-django and javascript libraries. Rest framework is used for constructing API.
MODULE 4: SSO - Single Sign Login	 Single sign login system which handles all products sign with LDAP (light weight directory access protocol) integrated. Developed using python django, restframework and angularJS.

MODULE 1: Report Mailer system	 Generating async mails for our all mailers using celery with rabbitmq message protocol It creates task queues for which regular mails generated with different formats, are send to clients. It uses angularjs and python django. SOFTWARE ENGINEER
	Emtex Engineering Pvt. Ltd. from 2015 to 2016. Developed and Enhanced leading E-ecommerce platform (http://www.industrybuying.com/) for selling and purchasing industrial products. Worked on various different set of modules as:
MODULE 1: Developed SMS Infrastructure	 Integration of SMS india hub API for devloping functionality of sending text messages to customers for orders like booking sms, shipping sms etc. Functionality was built on python Django framework with Front-End technologies.
MODULE 2: Google Tag Manager Integration	 Setting up GTM for tracking codes and pixels. Worked on GTM for integrating web tags and creating javascript variables to fire tags on conversion.
MODULE 3: Developed Clearance Sale Feature	 Developed clearance sale functionality on site for clearing stocks of products. Python Django framework and Front-End technologies were used for development. Also worked on SOLR for getting product for clearance. Setup SOLR field in schema.
MODULE 4: Developed Brand Pages CMS Architecture	 Created brand pages for showing top selling brands, popular brands, banners and clearance sale on brands with CMS portal to make content adjustable. Built on Python Django framework and Front-End technologies. Used MongoDB for data storage.

MODULE 5: Google PLA Substructure	With Google Merchant Center, sub-structured product feed in Low, Popular, High priced products in XML feed format in Python Django, Which was running on CRON machine.
MODULE 6: Google Adwords Search Ads Automation	 Built system to form Search Ads at Google Adwords for all products data. Setting Campaigns, Keywords, Adgroups using programming methodologies. Integrated Google Adwords API, Google Analytics API for Search Ads operations on Python Django framework.
MODULE 7: Quotation To Cart Functionality	 Developed Functionality of adding Quotations by customers and saving them and later convert them to cart. Send Email containing quotations. Handling Price Updations and out of stock products. Used Python Django framework and Front-End technologies.

EDUCATION

B.TECH (Computer Science Engineering).

Academic Qualification

Qualification	Institution	Year of study	<u>%</u>
B. TECH (Computer science engineering)	Guru Tegh Bahadur Institute of Technology, Delhi (Affilated to GGSIPU)	2011-2015	75
12 th	St. Mary's Sr. Sec. School, Haridwar (CBSE)	2011	75
10 th	St. Mary's Sr. Sec. School, Haridwar (CBSE)	2009	87

STRENGTH PERSONAL PROFILE

Able to work efficiently and effectively. Willingness to learn.

Ability to adapt to changes effectively.

Eager to take up challenging opportunities in life.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Sex	Female
<u>Nationality</u>	Indian
<u>DOB</u>	03-05-1993
Language Known	English, Hindi
Permanent Address	Hno. 717/420, Street NO. 3, Arya Nagar, Jwalpur, Haridwar-249407